製作: 星際迷航中國字幕組 (https://www.startrekchina.org)
翻譯: 諾北 & 北窗高臥久息塵 & 銅綠 & Enterprise-H & Bruce & 凌塔
校對: narwhrl
時軸: narwhrl
特效: narwhrl
日期: 2025-07-20
《星際迷航: 新世界》前情提要
Previously on Star Trek: Strange New Worlds...
向在通訊範圍內的所有聯邦星艦求救
To any Federation vessels in range, need help.
遭遇戈恩人襲擊
Under attack by the Gorn.
如今星際聯邦和戈恩霸權的關係非常緊張
The Federation's at a dangerous point in our relationship with the Gorn Hegemony.
這看起來像是一條分界線
It looks like a demarcation line.
帕納索斯貝塔星和他們所有的武裝力量
With Parnassus Beta and all their forces
在這條線的另一邊
on the far side of the line.
不幸的是 我認為我們的人
Unfortunately, that is where
被關押在那裡
I believe our people are being held.
我不打算丟下他們不管
I don't plan on leaving them behind.
如果我頭腦裡藏著的東西是拯救進取號的答案
If somewhere in my head is the answer to saving the Enterprise,
那我必須冒這個險
then that's a risk I have to take.
拿著這個
Take this.
它能幫你藏起來
It'll help you hide.
快跑
Run!
在下蒙哥馬利·斯考特
Montgomery Scott at your service.
你怎麼還活著
How are you not dead?
我知道如何隱藏在眾目睽睽之下
Well, I figured out how to hide in plain sight.
你造了個戈恩人的應答器嗎
You built a Gorn transponder?
總的來說 對於掃描儀而言
Eh, basically, to a scanner,
我們的穿梭機看起來像是戈恩飛船
the shuttle looked like a Gorn ship.
你還能再造一個類似之前的設備嗎
Could you build another device like the one you made?
發生什麼了
What's happening?
巴特爾艦長需要馬上注射鎮定劑
Captain Batel is in need of immediate sedation.
昨天發生的
Happened yesterday.
我不會放棄她的
I'm not giving up on her.
我也沒那個打算
I have no intention of doing that.
艦長 傳送機目前在星球表面上未探測到任何人
Captain, the transporter is not currently picking up anyone on the surface.
艾普里爾上將命令我們馬上撤離
Admiral April's ordering our immediate withdrawal.
殖民地居民和外勤隊
The colonists and the landing party
顯然被傳送到了
appear to have been beamed up
戈恩人的船上
by the Gorn.
艦長 請下令
Orders, Captain?
現在 即將揭曉結局
And now, the conclusion.
艦長 請下令
Orders, Captain?
護盾只剩50%了
Shields at 50%.
艦長
Captain.
艦長 請下令
Orders, Captain?
烏乎拉 再重複一下上將剛剛的命令
Uhura, repeat April's last order.
撤退 並且
Retreat and rendez...
撤退並與艦隊匯合 艦長
Retreat and rendezvous with the fleet, sir.
他給了坐標
He gave coordinates.
但他沒說要立即會合 對吧
But he didn't say immediately?
行了 各位有什麼點子嗎
All right, who's got ideas?
聲東擊西
Diversionary tactics.
我們被圍困得太厲害了
We're too boxed in.
排空曲速艙 製造一片等離子云團?
Vent the nacelles, create a cloud?
那我們自己也看不見了
We need to be able to see.
干擾敵方的通訊
Jam their comms
使其無法協調攻擊
so they can't coordinate attacks.
對 就是這個
That's it. That's the one.
戈恩人使用光信號作為艦對艦通訊手段
The Gorn use light for ship-to-ship messaging.
我正在調整偏導陣列來發射光譜
I'm modulating the deflector array to emit a spectrum.
應該能迷惑他們一陣
Should confuse them for a bit.
好 現在想想要怎麼把自己人傳送回來
All right, now how do we beam our people back to Enterprise?
掃描顯示戈恩星艦能夠阻斷傳送
Scans indicate the Gorn ships are transport-resistant.
所以即便我們繞過了護盾
So, even if we get past the shields,
也需要授權碼才行
we need authorization codes.
沒時間去破解密碼了
No time to hack codes.
先撤再救
Retreat and rescue.
這是一堆爛選項裡最好的了
It's the best of a bunch of bad options.
那我們要怎樣追蹤一艘
So how do we track this specific ship
跨越數光年的船呢
across light-years of space?
沃凱礦 一種稀有元素
Wolkite. A rare element
含有子空間規範玻色子
that contains subspace gauge bosons.
如果我們調整一個定位信標
If we modified a homing beacon...
戈恩人遠遠地就能看到信標飛過來
The Gorn would see a beacon coming from a mile away.
如果是魚雷就不會
Not if it's a torpedo.
我們對他們發射一顆啞彈
We tag 'em with a dud.
戈恩人猜不到我們要幹什麼
The Gorn won't know what we're up to.
護盾只剩30%了
Shields at 30%.
要想這個方法奏效 我們仍需穿透
For this to succeed, we still need to penetrate
戈恩星艦的護盾系統
the Gorn's defensive systems.
我們已經用上了所有武器攻擊他們
We've been hitting them with everything we've got,
沒多大用
it doesn't do much.
能量護盾基於諧波運作
Uh, energy shields work on harmonics.
如果我們找對頻率
If we find the right frequency...
我們可以撞擊敵艦
We can ram the ship.
確實
Indeed.
我們的護盾和他們的接觸時
When our shields make contact with theirs,
兩列諧波疊加時會出現相消干涉現象
they will create a destructive interference pattern
並在短時間內中斷這兩個頻率的護盾
and momentarily interrupt both frequencies.
沒有護盾 我們就是活靶子
With our shields down, we'd be sitting ducks.
那我們就只有一次機會
We'd only have one shot.
這就足夠了
That's all we need.
米歇爾 調轉方向
Mitchell, bring us around,
與敵方驅逐艦正面交火
head-to-head with the destroyer.
是時候來點硬碰硬了
Time to play a game of chicken.
全艦注意 做好衝擊準備
All decks, prepare for impact.
隨時可讓脈衝引擎全速推進 艦長
Full impulse on your orders, Captain.
讓慣性阻尼器最大功率運行
Inertial dampeners to maximum.
所有人 抓穩扶好了
Everybody hold onto something.
烏娜
Una...
動手吧
let's hit it.
發射魚雷
Fire torpedoes.
舵手 曲速帶離
Helm, warp us out of here.
遵命
On it.
堅持住 各位
Hang in there, guys.
艦長 我們已到達會合點
Captain, we've arrived at the rendezvous point.
聯邦星艦巴勃羅·畢加索號在聯絡我們
The USS Pablo Picasso is hailing to greet us.
是艾普里爾上將 艦長
It's Admiral April, sir.
他現在要傳送上艦聽取匯報
He's beaming aboard now to debrief.
還要打針嗎
More needles?
沒錯 得再來幾針
Yes, just a few more pokes.
沒有這些
I mean, without these,
你的身體會在靜滯場裡面壞死 所以
your body will go necrotic in the stasis field, so...
你會變紫 會很難看
Things turn purple. It's not pretty.
我從沒被凍結冬眠過
I've never been frozen solid before.
這前景不怎麼激動人心
It's not an exciting prospect.
沒事 等我們解決了這小小的戈恩卵感染問題
Well, as soon as we work out this little Gorn infection,
你就又能活蹦亂跳的了
you'll be up and around again.
（* 原文是指小說《瑞普·凡·溫克爾》裡主人公一覺睡了二十年 醒來發現世界已經天翻地覆）
感覺我會像小說裡瑞普*那樣 一醒來發現一切都變了
So this could be like a Rip Van Winkle thing for me.
我覺得你更會像是睡美人
I see you more as a Sleeping Beauty.
聽著 我之前說的是認真的
Listen, I meant what I said before.
一旦那時要在我和其他船員之間做出選擇
The moment it looks like me or the crew,
就犧牲掉我
you take me out.
不要想這些了
Don't think about that.
靜滯狀態會阻止你和戈恩胚胎
Stasis will prevent you and the Gorn
進行任何形式的細胞生長
from any type of cellular growth.
做好最壞的打算
There's another side to the coin.
無論代價如何
Whatever it takes.
無論代價如何 我保證
Whatever it takes. I promise.
我現在要給你注射鎮靜劑了
I'm, uh, I'm gonna give you a sedative now.
等你醒來 戈恩感染的問題就治好了
And when you wake up, you will be Gorn-free.
腎上腺素和中和劑 快
Epinephrine and neutralizer, stat!
她的身體正在排斥血清
Her body's rejecting the serum.
醫務室呼叫艦橋
Sickbay to bridge.
有個最新消息 情況不太樂觀
Uh, I have an update, and it's not good.
告訴我最壞情況
Bottom line it for me.
巴特爾艦長對低溫血清過敏
Captain Batel is allergic to cryoserum.
我們不能把她放進靜滯狀態
We can't put her in stasis.
那她的生命已經進入倒計時了嗎
So she's back on a ticking clock?
她身體裡的戈恩卵會在
The Gorn will hatch from her body in, um...
一天之內孵化
in less than a day.
我正在努力尋找治療的方法
I'm stuck trying to find a treatment.
但是
Um... uh...
也許如果約瑟夫在這裡 就可以
maybe if Joseph was here, I could...
我會派人去幫忙
I'm sending help.
克莉絲汀
Christine...
我相信你
I believe in you.
救救她
Help her.
我會盡我所能 艦長
I'll do my best, Captain.
艦長 我或許不是醫生
Captain, I may not be a doctor,
但我能夠把我所有的能力都奉獻在巴特爾艦長的治療上
but I will dedicate all of my abilities to Captain Batel
直到解決她的戈恩卵感染
until her Gorn infection is... resolved.
就只是看著?
Just stand by?
你可是有一整支艦隊在待命啊
You have the entire fleet out there ready to go.
這是力量展示
It's a show of force.
我們先要建立起有效的巡邏
First we need to establish patrols.
他們真這麼覺得嗎
Do they really think
覺得戈恩人只要炸完這些殖民地
the Gorn are just gonna stop and go home
就會收手然後回家?
after they raided those colonies?
好吧 這是很棘手的情況
Look, it's a tough situation,
但我們必須一次解決一個問題
but we have to manage it one piece at a time.
無數無辜生命正危在旦夕 鮑勃
There are innocent lives at stake, Bob.
我明白
And I get that.
但這件事發生在我們的管轄範圍之外
But it's happening outside of our jurisdiction.
拜託 鮑勃
Oh, come on, Bob.
除了你那不怕死的狗斗之外
Apart from your reckless dogfight,
這些攻擊和聯邦並沒有關係
these attacks do not involve the Federation.
我們有規定的 克里斯
We have regulations, Chris.
所以 就因為死的不是聯邦公民
So, because it's non-Federation citizens that are dying,
我們就作壁上觀嗎
we do nothing?
我們對於聯邦成員國都有義務在身
We have an obligation to our member worlds.
那可是數十億人
Billions of lives.
現在就貿然投入戰爭
To rush into a fight right now
會將所有人都置於危險當中
puts all of them at risk.
我們不能這樣
We can't do it.
我們還沒從克林貢戰爭中完全恢復
We're still recovering from the Klingon War.
你說得一點沒錯
You are absolutely right,
戈恩就是利用這一點發動進攻
and the Gorn sense our weakness.
我們現在是獵物
We are prey.
他們只會把這條霸權的邊境線
They will push this Hegemony line
向著聯邦領空內部推得越來越深
further and further into Federation space.
你也知道他們會這麼做
And you know they will.
等到我們真的恢復過來
And by the time we actually get around
有精力反制的時候
to doing something about it...
一切就太晚了
it'll be way too late.
我聽說了外勤隊的事
I heard about the landing party.
對啊 還有幾百號殖民地居民呢
Yeah, and a couple hundred colonists, too.
瑪麗呢
And Marie?
她在醫務室裡
She's in sickbay.
官方地說 給你的命令是監控分界線
Officially, your orders are to monitor the demarcation line
避免戈恩人的進一步進犯
for any encroachment by the Gorn.
好 那不官方的呢
Okay. And unofficially?
為何不給他們點顏色看看 告訴他們我們不是獵物
How do we punch back and show them we aren't prey?
行 我接受這個
Yeah, I can do that.
你做的這個裝置
This contraption of yours,
你再說一遍它是幹什麼的
what's it supposed to do again?
發射極化電磁信號
Emit a polarized EM signature that
誘騙戈恩 讓它們以為我們是他們中的一員
tricks the Gorn into thinking we're one of them.
類似隱身裝置的原理
It's like a cloaking device.
那麼它究竟是怎麼做到這一點的
And how, exactly, does it do that?
說實話 我不太記得了
Ah, if I'm being honest, I don't really remember.
我就是當時靈機一動
I was kind of in the moment.
很好 那我現在要問一個很蠢的問題
Well, now I'm going to ask a silly question,
而且我確定我知道答案
to which I'm pretty sure I know the answer.
別又來這個
Not this again.
就像回到了報告廳一樣
It's like being back in lecture hall.
你怎麼知道 你又沒去過報告廳
How would you know that? You were never there.
我去過 在後排而已
I was there, in the back.
你在把這堆東西拼起來時
Did you record a work-in-progress log
有沒有記工作日誌
while you were jury-rigging this up?
啥 您的意思是在戈恩人正在轟炸我的時候記錄?
What, you mean as the Gorn were tearing our ship apart?
斯考特 工程學第一定律就是寫下來
First rule in engineering, Scotty: write it down.
我們被要求無論什麼情況下
There's a reason we track our work
都要記錄自己的工作是有理由的
no matter what the circumstance, and this,
現在的這個情況 就是最好的理由
this right now, this is precisely the reason.
抱歉打斷
Pardon the interruption.
你們還要多久能讓這東西恢復運作
How long before you get that working?
哦 派克艦長 問題是
Oh, Captain Pike, the thing is,
它在我的小穿梭機上能起作用
it worked on my wee shuttle,
但進取號就
but the Enterprise is...
那您什麼時候需要它呢 艦長
How soon do you need it, Captain?
我們正在航向戈恩的領空
We're headed into Gorn space,
所以現在能用就最好了
so now would be good.
在我們跨過分界線之前它會準備好的
It'll be up and working before we cross the Hegemony line.
我希望如此 因為我和船上所有人的命都指望在它身上了
I'm counting on it, as are the lives of everyone on board.
不管有沒有這個裝置
We're going after our missing crew,
我們都要去搜救被抓走的船員
with or without that device.
明白了嗎
Understand?
哇 還真是一點壓力都沒有呢
Well, that's no pressure.
媽媽
Mom?
拉安 勇敢點
La'An, be brave.
對危險沒有畏懼之心才會置你於死地
Not believing you're gonna die is what gets you killed.
那是戈恩人
It's the Gorn.
醒醒
Wake up.
快醒醒
Wake up!
你能做到的
You can do this.
第一個倒霉的總是醫生
Always start with the doctor.
好了
Okay.
我的媽 我的手
Holy crap, my hand!
我他媽的半隻手都沒了
Half my hand is frickin' gone.
艾麗卡 看著我
Erica, look at me.
看著我 冷靜下來
Look at me. Relax.
會沒事的
It's going to be okay.
只要我們能回到船上就能治好它
We can fix this when we get back to the ship.
拜託
Please.
先保持冷靜
Try to stay calm.
好吧
Okay.
但怎麼
How?
我們怎麼才能回到船上
How do we get back to the ship?
而且他們怎麼辦
What about them?
如果我們一次只能解救一個人
If we free them one at a time,
那我們能救出來的人屈指可數
we'll only get a handful out.
如果能的話
If that.
光是我們四個人脫困就花了這麼久
Look how long it took for the four of us to get loose.
這是一個巨大的消化腔
This is a massive digestive chamber.
而且它正在消化
And it's working its way through...
看起來像是燃料加工廠
looks like a-a processing plant for fuel.
或者只是戈恩人的食物工廠
Or just food for the Gorn.
我真的不想變成哪個戈恩人的盤中餐
I don't like the idea of being anyone's lunch.
即便我們能夠喚醒他們
And even if we can wake them up,
不管是一個還是一百個
one or a hundred,
我們還是沒法離開這個
we still don't have a way out of...
不知道什麼的地方
wherever this is.
先一步一步來吧
One step at a time.
要是什麼都不做 就是等死
Sitting here doing nothing is a death sentence.
而且搞不好
And for all we know,
那些戈恩人可能在我們醒來那會就被驚動了
the Gorn were alerted the moment that we woke up.
所以那些殺人蜥蜴可能已經在來的路上了
So the killer lizards could already be on their way.
他們來了
They're coming.
別害怕
Don't be afraid.
拉安
La'An.
無論發生什麼
No matter what.
拉安
La'An.
上尉 你在想什麼
What's on your mind, Lieutenant?
你說得對
You're right.
不僅僅關乎我們自己
It's not just about us.
這些殖民地居民很快也會被殺害
All of these people will be dead soon.
看這
Hey.
這看起來像個排泄樁
This looks like an evacuation pile.
也許 這艘船不能處理的東西 都由它排出
Maybe whatever the ship can't process, it expels.
糞堆裡的武器
Weapons from a crap pile.
怪了 這個方向是對的
Strangely, it's a step in the right direction.
我不想只救下屈指可數的人
I don't want to save a handful of colonists,
我想拯救全部人
I want to save them all.
所有還活著的人 都能回家
Everyone that's still alive gets home.
即使這意味著 我們必須殺出一條血路
Even if we have to shoot our way out.
哎呀 你個蠢貨
Ack, bawheid.
不是這樣
That's not it.
是戈恩人 他們來了
They're here!
該死
Oh, shite.
我們完蛋了 斯考提
We're doomed. Scotty.
不不不不
No, no, no, no...
我們都死定了
We're all gonna die!
成功了
It's working.
快通知艦橋 把它加到護盾上
Tell the bridge to patch it to the shields.
怎麼 太晚了嗎
What? Is it too late?
艦橋呼叫科學實驗室 你們進展如何了
Bridge to science lab. What's the status down there?
我們馬上要進入戈恩領空了
We're about to enter Gorn space.
真是狡猾
Oh, you minx.
已經在正常運行了 艦長
It's up and running, Captain.
我們現在就能把它加到護盾上
We can patch it into the shields now.
好極了 派克完畢
Excellent. Pike out.
一點都不好笑
That wasn't funny.
明明就很有趣
It was fun.
你差點害我心臟病發作
You nearly gave me a heart attack.
我那麼做 是因為我了解你
I did it 'cause I know you.
你才不了解呢
No, you don't.
太了解了 平時閒得發慌的時候你就擺了
Yes, with too much time on your hands, you fall apart,
但要是有相位槍頂著你的頭 你立刻精神百倍
but put a phaser to your head and voilà.
你管我這麼多幹嘛
Why do you care what I do?
你防備太重了 斯考提
You put up walls, Scotty.
你太害怕承擔風險了
You're too afraid to take a risk.
我修好了你想讓我修的東西
I fixed what you wanted me to.
而且你相當目無上級
And you're insubordinate to boot.
準確來說你又不是我的上級
Well, technically you're not my C.O.
她在馭星號上犧牲了
She went down on the Stardiver.
我可以離開了嗎 長官
May I be excused, sir?
哦 斯考提
Oh, Scotty.
艦長 我們正在接近戈恩霸權領空邊境
Approaching the Hegemony demarcation line now, sir.
脫離曲速
Drop us out of warp.
開啟斯考特的應答器
Start Mr. Scott's transponder.
應答器?
Transponder?
佩利亞說它更像是一個改裝過的電磁脈衝發射器
Pelia says it's more like a modified EM pulse emitter.
好吧 那就說得通了
Okay, then that makes sense.
戈恩人肯定不使用光學數據
The Gorn must not use optical data.
他們已經進化了
They've evolved,
所以他們一定依賴生物識別信息
so they must rely on biometrics,
熱量和電磁信號
heat and EM signatures.
嗯 是時候看看這到底能不能成功了
Well, time to see if it actually works.
我的意思是 它應該可以
It should. I mean,
除非哪個戈恩人突然決定看一眼窗外
unless maybe one of them decides to look out a window.
艦長 戈恩狩獵艦正在接近
Captain, Gorn hunters approaching.
保持穩定航線
Keep us steady and on course.
目前為止 我沒看到任何窗戶
So far, I don't see any windows.
它奏效了
It worked.
烏乎拉 我們還能接收到沃凱礦信標的信號嗎
Uhura, do we still have a signal from the wolkite beacon?
是的 艦長
Aye, sir.
信號很弱且在逐漸減弱 但它還在發射信號
It's faint and getting weaker but still there.
有關於他們去向的情報嗎
Any intel on where they're headed?
一個未知的雙星系統
An uncharted binary star system.
那裡的恆星活動
The stellar activity there
是我們前所未見的
is like nothing we've ever seen before.
舵手 設置航線
Helm, plot a course.
艦長 那個星系的輻射高得超出量表
Captain, the radiation in that system is off the charts.
到最後 我們只能使用脈衝引擎
At a certain point, we can only use impulse engines,
進取號的護盾也無法抵擋輻射了
and our shields won't be able to protect us.
了解 那我們快速行動
Understood. We'll make it quick.
米歇爾 曲速七級
Mitchell, warp factor seven.
遵命 艦長
Aye aye, sir.
有趣
Intriguing.
戈恩卵的孵化進程大幅改變了她身體的生物化學結構
The incubation has severely altered her biochemistry.
她的身體現在依賴於戈恩的幼體
Her body is now as dependent
就像戈恩幼體依賴於她
on the Gorn hatchlings as they are on her.
完美的宿主 不可分割
The perfect host, inseparable.
你試過顯微減瘤術了嗎
Have you tried microscopic debulking?
模擬完畢
Results completed.
這是我最後跑的一次模擬
It's the last simulation I ran.
死亡率為100%
Probability of fatality is 100%.
我做的每一次模擬 結果全都一樣
That's the chorus of the day. It's every simulation I've run.
計算機 模擬顯微減瘤術的情境
Computer, run scenarios for microscopic debulking
將注射扎多拉提取物納入模擬變量中
factoring for an infusion of Zadora extract.
正在處理
Processing.
獵戶星的街頭毒品?
An Orion street drug?
實話說 這真是天才想法
Actually, that's kind of brilliant.
是你教會了我跳出框架去看
You are the one who taught me to look outside of the box.
是「去思考」
It's "think,"
但也差不多
but close enough.
克莉絲汀
Christine.
我知道你想談談
I know you want to talk.
我會盡量簡短
I will be brief.
我只是想為你離開前
I simply want to apologize
我們之間的結局道個歉
for the way things ended before you left.
我當時情緒有點失控
I reacted poorly.
好了
Apology accepted.
原諒你了
We're good.
失去你的念頭
The thought of losing you,
深深困擾著我
it affected me deeply.
我理解
I understand.
事情變得複雜了
This has gotten complicated,
我不擅長應對複雜
and I am not good at complicated.
而我還是要離開三個月
And I am still going away for three months
去和羅傑·科爾比一起學習
to study with Roger Korby.
等我回來 再看看我們的狀態吧
When I get back, let's just see where we are then.
所以你是想說
So you are saying that perhaps
也許分開一段時間 對我們有好處嗎
some time apart might be good for us?
史波克
Spock.
是的
Yeah.
但不是說
But not like...
作為我們倆的我們
not like "us" us.
只是說
Like...
作為兩個個體的我們
us as people.
請別做那些你覺得浪漫的事
Please don't do something you think is romantic,
像是等我之類的
like wait for me or something.
扎多拉提取物情境模擬完畢
Zadora extract scenario completed.
死亡率為100%
Probability of fatality is 100%.
無論我們用什麼方法
No matter how we approach this,
巴特爾的人類基因
Batel's human DNA is...
都存在不足
Inadequate.
她的身體進入休克狀態
Her body goes into shock,
血壓開始下降
blood pressure drops.
最後死亡
And she dies.
哼 人類的身體始終有限
Huh. Human physiology.
但如果我們給她的基因幫點忙呢
What if we gave her some help there?
你已經有主意了
You have an idea.
伊勒利亞人的基因
Illyrian DNA.
烏娜的血液
Una's blood,
基因使其可以實時抵抗感染
it's designed to combat infections in real time.
一劑血清可以給巴特爾的免疫系統來一次大升級
A plasma injection could provide a boost to Batel's immunity.
這樣我們就能在不使其休克的前提下
And we could attempt the surgery
嘗試進行手術了
without her going into shock.
這樣做違反規定
It is against regulation,
但能挽救她的生命
but it could save her life.
計算機 模擬手術結果
Computer, run scenario for surgery
將注射伊勒利亞血清納入模擬變量中
factoring for a plasma transfusion from an Illyrian blood donor.
處理中
Processing.
你當時是怎麼說的來著
How did you put it once?
有些規則就是用來打破的?
Some rules are intended to be broken?
幾乎準確無誤了
Almost exactly it.
這就是機庫
There's the hangar.
好吧
Okay.
大家都了解計劃吧
Everyone's clear on the plan?
訪問這艘船的計算機主機
Access the ship's mainframe,
上傳戈恩星艦的傳送器密碼
upload the Gorn transporter codes...
把他們帶回進取號
Get them to the Enterprise.
要成功 我們必須偷一艘飛船 從這裡飛出去
To do that, we have to steal a ship and fly it out of here.
這個看起來沒什麼警戒措施
That one doesn't look guarded.
我們超有把握 一點都不是不可能任務
Totally got this, not impossible at all.
你什麼都能飛 是真的吧
And it's true you can fly anything, right?
別這麼沒禮貌 當然是真的
Don't be rude. Of course I can.
好
Okay.
來搞定那艘飛船吧
Let's get to that ship.
這是個好計劃
This is a good plan.
一定行得通
It's gonna work.
這是個好計劃
It's good. It's-it's...
是個好計劃 對嗎
It's a good plan, right?
當然了
It's a good plan.
沒錯 我們現在只需要
Yeah. Yeah. Now all we have to do is
別被戈恩人逮住
not get caught by the Gorn.
山姆
Sam.
你為啥要烏鴉嘴
Why would you say that?
不是姐們 這你也能怪我啊
What? Oh, come on, you can't blame me.
相位槍調到擊殺檔
Phasers to kill.
該走了
Time to go.
我和烏乎拉一直在鑽研
Uhura and I have been poring over
手頭能得到的戈恩人數據
all available data on the Gorn.
確認的襲擊 未被證實的目擊
Confirmed attacks, unverified sightings.
如果可能和戈恩人有關係 我們就檢查過一遍
If it might be a Gorn, we've checked it out.
比我們想像的信息多出很多
And there's a lot more out there than we thought.
你得稍微用點想像力
You have to squint a little.
但是每一次戈恩目擊事件
But every Gorn sighting correlates
都和某個特定的恆星活動規律正相關
to a pattern of specific stellar events.
日冕物質拋射
Coronal mass ejections.
我已經了解過了
I know this already, CMEs.
恆星耀斑爆發會引發強烈恆星風
Stellar flares can set off a frenzy.
是的 其活動遵循一定的規律
Yes, the attacks follow a pattern,
戈恩人的休眠也是如此
but so does Gorn inactivity.
這都是烏乎拉發現的
Uhura is the one who found it.
我們知道有很長一段時間
There are long periods of time
沒有任何戈恩人活動的報告
where no Gorn activity is reported.
甚至連一點風聲都沒有
Not so much as a rumor.
在那個時間段
And in those instances,
獨特的恆星活動似乎觸發了某些東西
there's unique stellar activity that seems to trigger...
休眠
Hibernation.
沒錯
Yes.
我們認為戈恩人有著漫長的休眠週期
We believe that the Gorn have a long hibernation cycle.
在適當的條件下 它們會變得溫順
Under the right conditions, they become docile.
我們可以利用這一點
We can use that.
我們的科學團隊協助了計算
The science team chipped in on the math
成功識別出X級太陽耀斑及其伴隨的上弓下沉流
and was able to isolate the presence of X-class flares
兩者在消失前均有明顯前兆
and supra-arcade downflows that precede their absence.
做的好 你們倆
Good work, both of you.
還有一點
There's something else.
數據表明
The data also suggests that
我們可能正處於戈恩人長期侵略行為的初期
we could be at the beginning of a long cycle of Gorn aggression.
這些襲擊可能預示著
These attacks could signal what
戈恩人即將發動全面入侵
could soon be a full-scale Gorn invasion.
艦長 我們將在兩分鐘後脫離曲速
Dropping out of warp in two minutes, sir.
謝謝你 米歇爾 我們這就來
Thank you, Mitchell. On our way.
史波克和查普爾知道自己在做什麼
Spock and Chapel know what they're doing.
我相信他們
I trust them
會好好利用我的血液
with a couple liters of my blood.
謝謝你
Thank you for that.
他們說這可能是她唯一的機會
They say it may be her only hope.
為了瑪麗 他們需要什麼我都願意提供
For Marie, they can take all they want.
這次任務不留存記錄
This mission's already off-the-record,
所以也沒什麼好報告的
so nothing to report.
克里斯
Chris,
聽一聽你自己的建議吧
take some of your own advice.
要抱有希望
Focus on hope.
伊勒利亞血液供給方案已完成
Illyrian blood donor scenario completed.
死亡概率為86%
Probability of fatality: 86%.
只有這個方案能讓她有一線生機
That's the first one that's given her any chance at all.
雖然成功率也不高
Albeit not a very high one.
按理說 不能在這種概率下進行手術
I mean, we can't do the surgery with these odds.
但總算有所進展了 我們繼續努力
We're on to something. Let's keep at it.
好的
Indeed.
我們已接近輻射區
We're near the radiation zone.
從現在起 只能使用脈衝引擎
From here on, it's impulse engines only.
米歇爾 你連續工作很久了
Mitchell, you've been running nonstop.
去換班吧
Call for relief.
恕我直言 在把所有人都救回來前
With respect, I'm not leaving the station
我絕不離開崗位
until we get everyone back.
明白了
Copy.
謝謝你
Thank you.
我收到了沃凱礦的信號
I have the wolkite signature.
即將接近敵方驅逐艦
We're coming up on the enemy destroyer.
我們多久能追上他們
How soon can we overtake them?
克里斯 我們可能來晚了
Chris, we may be too late.
他們已經進入了輻射區
They've already entered the radiation zone.
如果我們繼續深入當前星系
If we go any deeper into this star system,
全體船員都將陷入危險
we put the entire crew at risk.
舵手 立即停船
Helm, full stop.
主屏幕切換為遠距離觀測畫面
Put the long-range visual up on the main screen.
是我的錯覺 還是
Is it me, or does it look like
那艘船確實正朝著恆星的方向行駛?
that ship is going to fly right into that star?
我也看到了 簡直難以置信
I see it, I don't believe it.
遙測數據已確認 艦長
Telemetry confirms, Captain.
我們必須做點什麼
We have to do something.
你看
Look.
他們是失去動力了嗎
Did they just lose power?
不是
No.
我認為他們是故意的
I think it was intentional.
但為什麼呢
But why?
將全部備用能量傳輸至護盾
All auxiliary power to the shields.
盡可能爭取在輻射區停留的時間
Give me as much time as possible inside that radiation zone.
我們追上去
We're going after 'em.
新一輪日冕物質拋射活動逼近
We've got another CME flare coming.
她快不行了
She's coding.
戈恩幼體正在孵化
The Gorn hatchlings are activating.
有什麼東西加速了它們的生長
Something has accelerated their growth.
14%的成功率總比注定的死亡要好
A 14% chance of survival is better than certain death.
準備手術吧
Let's prep her for surgery.
我還能接收到沃凱礦的信號
I'm still getting a ping on the wolkite signal.
我們必須盡我們所能拯救我們的船員
We need to get to our people while we still can.
這裡的磁場干擾讓導航系統無法運作
The magnetic fields here make navigation impossible.
這就解釋了戈恩星艦為何會像失去動力一樣
That explains why the Gorn go into a free fall.
他們利用了強重力井來完成大部分機動
They let the intense gravity wells do most of the work.
星際艦隊方面沒有回覆
No response from Starfleet.
都是因為這些輻射
It's all the radiation.
無論是進取號還是雙星系統以外的區域
And no visuals on the ship
都無法獲得影像反饋
or what's beyond the binary stars.
這種光線折射方式會生成一種自然全息投影
The light bends in a way that creates a natural hologram.
一旦穿過它 就無法被看到了
They're essentially invisible once they pass through it.
形成了絕佳的防禦屏障
Makes for a great defense system.
也許那是一種降落程序
Maybe it's a landing sequence.
有沒有可能 戈恩母星就在這
Could this be the Gorn homeworld?
如果假設成立 那這就是他們回母星的方法
If it is, that's how they go back to it.
艦長
Captain,
外面有情況
something's moving out there.
屏顯
On screen.
一號
Number One.
我計算了他們的軌跡
I've plotted their trajectory.
那些艦船正徑直駛向聯邦領空
Those ships are headed straight for Federation territory.
警告星際艦隊
Warn Starfleet.
只能使用深空通訊中繼聯絡
It's a deep space relay.
我無法確實他們是否收到了訊息
I won't be able to confirm if they receive it.
我們得走了
We need to go.
離開該星系的干擾範圍
Get clear of this system's interference.
艦長 如果我們現在失去沃凱礦的信號
Captain, if we lose our lock on the wolkite signal,
我無法保證我們能再次進行追蹤
I'm not sure we can reestablish contact.
我們會失去外勤小隊和殖民地居民
We'll lose the landing party and the colonists.
我們可以放置一個遠程通信浮標
We can drop a long-range communication buoy.
將信號連接到浮標上
Tie a signal to it.
這樣我們回來時就能找到他們了
That way we can come back for them.
這是我能想到的最好辦法了
It's the best I've got.
就這麼做
Do it.
我們必須阻止這場入侵
We have to stop this invasion.
通信浮標已部署
Communication buoy is deployed.
米歇爾 持續鎖定敵方艦隊
Mitchell, stay on that enemy fleet.
調轉艦艏
Bringing her about.
盡快曲速離開這裡
As soon as we can, you warp out of here.
全速前進 直到我們能夠將警報發給星際艦隊
Full throttle until we can alert Starfleet.
現在我們是聯邦唯一的指望了
We're the only hope the Federation's got right now.
（* 此處查普爾和史波克穿的防護服與《原初系列》1x06 “The Naked Time” 中穿著的防護服是同一樣式）
計算機 啟動隔離模式
Computer, engage quarantine mode.
隔離模式已啟動
Quarantine mode engaged.
如果失敗的話 這就是法雷奧貝塔*的悲劇重演
If this goes sideways, it's, it's Valeo Beta all over again.
（* 見《奇異新世界》1x09 聯邦星艦遊隼號上爆發戈恩寄生疫情 墜毀在法雷奧貝塔五星）
戈恩卵疫情在全艦爆發的可能性將會是
The probability of a full-scale Gorn outbreak...
我真的不想知道
I really don't want to know.
查普爾護士 聯邦星艦進取號
Nurse Chapel, USS Enterprise...
向患者巴特爾注射
...injecting Patient Batel
實驗性血漿溶液
with experimental plasma solution.
有進展嗎 少尉
Anything, Ensign?
通訊仍受阻礙 艦長
Still jammed, sir.
戈恩人正在發送干擾信號
The Gorn are transmitting an interference signal.
距我們離開雙星系統進入曲速還有多久
How long before we clear these binary stars and go to warp?
時間不夠
Not soon enough.
戈恩星艦的航速比我們快得多
Those Gorn ships are moving a lot faster than we are.
等警告發出
By the time we get a signal out,
戈恩艦隊已經到達聯邦外圍成員國的位置了
the Gorn will be right on top of the outer Federation worlds.
他們只能坐以待斃
They're sitting ducks.
米歇爾 我們在戈恩艦隊的武器射程內嗎
Mitchell, are we in shooting distance of the Gorn?
克里斯
Chris,
你要讓進取號對陣整個戈恩艦隊嗎
Enterprise against an entire armada?
我們根本不是對手
We wouldn't stand a chance.
派克呼叫科學實驗室
Pike to science lab.
佩利亞 我需要你到艦橋來
Pelia, I need you on the bridge.
好的 艦長 馬上來
Aye, Captain, right away.
你打算做什麼
What are you up to?
你和烏乎拉
You and Uhura,
你們之前說恆星耀斑決定了
you said stellar flares can dictate
戈恩人的狩獵和休眠週期
a Gorn's hunting and resting cycles.
確實如此
Right.
我們甚至知道哪種輻射信號
We even know precisely what kind of radiation signature
可以讓戈恩人陷入休眠
would tell the Gorn to go to sleep.
艦長 這只是理論上的
Um, sir, that's just a theory.
所以
So...
我們只需要人為製造一場恆星耀斑爆發
...we just need to create a stellar flare.
抱歉打斷您 艦長
Oh, forgive me for interrupting,
但我們基本沒辦法對恆星造成什麼影響
but you cannot make a star do much of anything.
更別說是精確控制耀斑爆發了
Certainly not precisely, Captain.
所以我們需要自己成為一次日冕物質拋射
Which is why we need to become a CME, uh,
也就是X級耀斑
X-flare ourselves.
艦長 你看
Captain, look.
抱歉 你介意騰位置嗎
Uh, sorry, do you mind?
嗯是 用星艦來操作
Eh, sure, using the ship
的確能讓我們精準調控發射的輻射和電磁信號
would allow us to modulate the exact radiation and EM signals we'd emit.
但你說的基本上就是
But you're basically talking about
把整艘船變成一顆人造恆星
turning the ship into an artificial star.
這基本上是不可能的
That's-that's nearly impossible.
但並非完全不可能
But not impossible.
為了達到這個目的 我們必須深入到
To do that, we'd have to go deeper
這個致死的輻射區裡
into this deadly radiation zone,
徑直飛過外面那對雙星之間
fly right between those binary stars out there,
想辦法製造一個對抗磁場
and create some kind of competing magnetic field
將粒子從雙星中引開
to draw particles away from both of them.
需要調整偏導護盾 通訊陣列 還有
Modify the deflector shields, comms array, and, well...
基本上系統都得重改一遍
every-everything else, really.
連艦體都要磁化 才能吸引恆星物質
Magnetize the hull to attract stellar material.
成功的機率是千分之一
It's one in a thousand we'd get it done right
要麼能完成任務要麼炸飛自己 看吧
or don't blow ourselves up along the way, and, look.
我也不確定 但我願意賭一把
Yeah, I don't know. I like those odds.
我們就
We'll just...
在爆炸前把它關閉
...turn it off before we blow up.
就這麼辦
Get it done.
患者對輸血反應良好
Patient is responding favorably to the transfusion.
準備進行第一次手術切口
Ready to make the first incision.
等一下
Wait.
你知道最壞的情況是巴特爾艦長會殉職
You know the most likely outcome is the death of Captain Batel?
我們只是需要一點信心
We just have to have a little faith.
或許我們是從錯誤的角度來看待這件事的
Perhaps we are looking at this from the wrong perspective.
與其在治療巴特爾上花時間
Instead of operating on Batel,
要是我們試著去對付一下戈恩人呢
what if we treated the Gorn inside of her?
它們想要孵化出來覓食
We know they emerge to feed.
要是我們給它們餵食呢
What if we feed them?
把它們餵飽 防止它們孵化
Satiate them to keep them from coming out.
當他們不再處於攻擊狀態時 把它們幹掉
And when they are no longer in defensive mode, dissolve them.
並用烏娜的伊勒利亞血漿
And use Una's Illyrian plasma
來對抗他們在重新吸收過程中
to fight the multitude of infections that will result
產生的大量感染
from their reabsorption.
沒錯
Yes.
但我們沒有時間再去模擬一次了
But we don't have enough time to run another simulation.
就像你剛才提議的那樣
As you suggested,
也許我們只是需要一點信心
perhaps we just need a little faith.
我們甩掉他們了嗎
Did we lose them?
或許吧
Maybe,
即便甩掉了 也是暫時的
but if so, then not for long.
這是個接口
This is an interface.
在戈恩的繁殖星球上
They had them on the Gorn...
也有這樣的裝置
the Gorn breeding planet.
我哥哥馬努 他
My brother Manu, he...
別害怕
Don't be afraid.
無論如何 別停下來
Keep moving, no matter what.
嘿
Hey.
你還好嗎
Are you okay?
你現在在這裡 而不是在過去的那個地方
You're here now, not back there.
是啊 但這裡也沒好到哪去 不是嗎
Yeah, but here's not great either, is it?
是啊 確實很糟糕
No, I suppose not.
我有印象了 讓我試試看
I remember. Let me try something.
太神奇了
This is amazing.
我很想把這個拆開 弄明白它是怎麼運作的
I'd love to take this apart, figure out how it works.
真是好主意
Yeah, good idea.
在這待上一天慢慢研究吧
Let's make a whole day of it.
吃點零食 在這閒逛
Get snacks, hang out.
那些看起來像是緩衝信號
Those look like buffer signatures.
是的 還有傳送授權碼
They are. And the transport codes.
如果我們能把這個送回進取號
If we can get this to the Enterprise,
就能救走殖民地的居民
then we can save the colonists.
拯救所有人
All of them.
大伙們
Guys...
快去船上
Get to the ship!
我們就位了
We are in position,
正在接近雙星
approaching the binary stars.
當我們關閉電磁脈衝發生器的瞬間
The moment we shut down the EM emitter,
每一艘戈恩星艦都會直奔我們而來
every single Gorn ship is going to come at us.
就像飛蛾撲火一樣
Like moths to a flame.
這也正是我們想要的效果
Which is exactly what we want.
大家準備好了嗎
Everybody ready?
像太陽一般閃耀吧
Make us shine like the sun.
駕駛位
The pilot seat.
讓我坐駕駛位
Put me in the pilot seat.
我來駕駛它
Put me in the pilot seat!
別逞強了
Forget about it!
我能讓它飛起來 這非我不可
I can fly it. It has to be me.
她說得對 我們必須得離開這
She's right. We need to go.
我們完全暴露在β粒子和伽馬射線中了
We're covered in beta particles and gamma rays.
星艦正在承受著臨界水平的輻射
This ship is hitting critical levels of radiation!
戈恩人在做什麼
What are the Gorn doing?
他們已經脫離編隊
They have broken ranks,
目前正處於進取號的攔截航線上
currently on intercept course with Enterprise.
目前看起來一切順利
All right, so far, so good.
現在看看它們會不會向我們開火
Now let's see if they shoot at us.
艦長 我收到了一個
Captain, I have a signal bouncing off
通訊信標反射的信號
the communications beacon.
是拉安 長官
It's La'An, sir.
進取號 能收到嗎
Enterprise, are you there?
拉安 你在哪
La'An, where are you?
在路上 如果能收到信號的話
On our way. If you can read me,
注意接收我向你們發送的傳送密碼
I'm sending you transport codes.
把帕納索斯人傳送出去
Beam the Parnassians out.
我們正在嘗試傳送
We're trying to beam you out,
但我們難以鎖定你們
but we're having trouble getting a lock.
你們收到了嗎
Do you copy?
它們正衝着我們來
They're gaining on us!
進取號 你們是否收到
Enterprise, do you read me?
把帕納索斯人傳送回艦
Beam the Parnassians out.
艦長 艦體完整性即將逼近極限
Captain, hull integrity is approaching critical failure!
把它關掉 關掉它
Turn it off. Turn it off!
起作用了嗎
Did it work?
沒錯 艦長 最後一艘戈恩船只已返回母星
Aye, sir, the last of the Gorn have gone home.
帕納索斯人呢
What about the Parnassians?
我們及時把他們傳回來了嗎
Did we get them out in time?
是的 艦長
Yes, Captain.
拉安的傳送密碼生效了
The transport codes from La'An worked.
幾百名殖民地居民已經被救回
Several hundred colonists accounted for
正在送往應急醫務室
and headed for the overflow infirmary.
艦長 我們急需--
Captain, we need immediate as--
將我們傳送上艦並讓一個醫療小組待命
Beam us out and have a medical team standing by.
派克呼叫輪機部
Pike to Engineering?
是 艦長 我們正在使用傳送碼
Aye, Captain, we're using the transport codes
破解戈恩狩獵艦的系統
to hack into the Gorn hunter,
應該很快就能搞定
should be just a moment.
克里斯 我們做到了
Chris. Chris, we did it.
我們引起了戈恩人的長時休眠
We triggered a long hibernation in the Gorn.
是啊
Yeah...
但我忍不住在想
But I can't help wondering
我們會不會只是把麻煩推給了未來的人們
if we didn't just create a problem for someone else to solve later.
艦長 我收到了艾普里爾上將的加密呼叫
Captain. I'm getting a secure channel from Admiral April.
接通
Put him through.
克里斯 我們剛收到你的優先級訊息
Chris. We just got your priority message.
在戈恩艦隊到這之前我們還有多少時間
How much time do we have before the Gorn ships get here?
請忽略最後一條訊息
Ignore last transmission.
至少在一段時間內我們見不著戈恩人
We won't be seeing the Gorn, at least not for a while.
你有幾分把握
How certain are you?
怎麼說呢 我已經對戈恩人還以顏色了
Let's just say I found a way to punch back.
保持清醒 別暈過去
Stay with me. Stay with me.
我做的很棒
I did good.
不是嗎
Didn't I?
別說話了 你能撐住的
Stop. You're going to make it.
想幹掉我 他們還不夠格
They'll have to try harder than that.
我可是艾麗卡·奧特加斯
I'm Erica Ortegas.
無敵舵手
I fly the ship.
撐住 有我在呢
Hold on. I got you.
我們盡力了
We did all we could.
現在要看巴特爾艦長自己了
It's in Captain Batel's hands now.
的確
Indeed.
謝謝你
Thank you.
沒有你的話 我沒法做到這一切
I couldn't have done that without you.
不用謝
You're welcome.
她怎麼樣了
How is she?
她在實驗室裡 仍在恢復中
She's in the lab, still in recovery.
外勤隊已經救回
Landing Party accounted for and
正在應急醫務室中接受治療
getting treatment in the overflow infirmary.
艾麗卡傷得很重
Erica is critical...
但目前穩定
but stable.
謝謝你的通知
Thanks for the update.
一旦我們離開輻射區域
Once we clear the radiation bands,
就設定航線回地球 曲速回家
chart a course for Earth. Warp us home.
遵命 一號完畢
Of course. Number One out.
好吧
Okay.
好吧 主
Okay, Dad.
你贏了
You win.
我們
Our Father,
在天上的主
who art in heaven...
克里斯
Chris?
你醒了
You're awake.
是啊 我想這意味著
Yeah. Which I assume means
那些小戈恩們還沒破肚而出
that tiny Gorn didn't pop out of my body
殺了大家呢
and kill everybody.
不
No.
當然沒有 我們都好好的呢
No, no, no. We're still here.
史波克和查普爾想出了治療方案
Spock and Chapel came up with a treatment, uh...
我後面會讓他們解釋給你聽
I'll have them walk you through it later, but...
但你還沒有完全脫離危險
...you're still not out of the woods yet.
怎麼做到的
How?
烏娜幫的忙
Una helped.
克里斯 你就不應該那麼做
Chris, you shouldn't have done that.
瑪麗 我已經失去了太多 好嗎
Marie, I've already lost too much, all right?
所以我們可以繼續爭
So we can sit here and we can argue about
爭論未來會不會發生什麼
what might or might not happen in the future,
但能不能把那些都放一邊 讓我抱著你
or you can just set all that aside and let me hold you.
我真的不能再失去你
I really don't want to lose you.
沒事了
I'm still here.
我還在呢